shuledirect.co.tz 2015-10-21

# Shule Direct

## Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy relates solely to information supplied by you at our web application [www.shuledirect.co.tz](http://www.shuledirect.co.tz/) and related mobile applications and services. Please read this policy with the [Terms of Use](http://www.shuledirect.co.tz/policy/terms).

### Introduction

﻿Shule Direct is committed to protecting your personal information when you are using our services. We want our services to be safe and enjoyable environments for our users. This Privacy Policy relates to our use of any personal information you provide to us via online registration, content usage, by email, in letters or correspondence.

It also relates to our use of any personal information you provide to us online or on mobile.

From time to time, we will need to collect information about you.

This Privacy Policy explains the following:

  * what information Shule Direct may collect about you;

  * how Shule Direct will use information we collect about you;

  * when Shule Direct may use your details to contact you;

  * whether Shule Direct will disclose your details to anyone else;

  * and your choices regarding the personal information you provide to us;

Shule Direct is committed to safeguarding your personal information. Whenever you provide such information, we pledge to be legally obliged with data protection legal provisions available locally and internationally.

We may also have third party websites linked to our web and mobile applications and you may have to review their privacy policies before using them. We do not accept any responsibility or liability for the privacy practices of such third party websites and your use of such websites is at your own risk.

### Information about you

﻿When you participate in, access or sign up to any of Shule Direct's services, activities or online content, such as the API, the web application, discussion forum, newsletters, competitions, live chats, notice boards, emails, social networks or create an account using our online registration system we may receive personal information about you. This can consist of information such as your name, email address, mobile number, date of birth, educational institution/school, level of education or gender depending on the activity.

By submitting your details, you enable Shule Direct (and where applicable its contractors) to provide you with the services, activities or online content you select.

Please note that sometimes we will require you to provide additional personal information for purposes of research. When we do this we will provide further information as to why we are collecting your information and how we will use it.

Shule Direct collect IP addresses from visitors of the web application. We also remotely track their usage of the content for purposes of analytics collection. This information is quantitative and may not necessarily contain private (qualitative) information.

### How we will use your personal information

﻿Shule Direct will use your personal information;

  * To provide our services and online content and to deal with your enquiries;

  * For "service administration purposes", which means that Shule Direct may contact you for reasons related to the service or online content you have signed up for.

  * To contact you about a submission or enquiry you have made, including any content you provide.

  * To provide you with information about our services, activities or online content;

  * To personalise the way Shule Direct content is presented to you

  * To use IP addresses to identify the location of users, to block disruptive use, to establish the number of visits from different locations;

  * To analyse and improve the services offered on Shule Direct web and mobile;

  * To provide you with the most user-friendly user experience on our applications. When Shule Direct uses your personal information for any other uses we will ensure that we notify you first. You will also be given the opportunity to withhold or withdraw your consent for the use of your personal information for purposes other than those listed above.

**Notifying you**

Shule Direct may contact you:

  * In relation to any service or online content you have signed up for in order to ensure that Shule Direct can deliver the services to you;

  * In relation to any enquiry or correspondence we receive from you or any comment or complaint you make about Shule Direct products or services;

  * In relation to any contribution you have submitted to Shule Direct;

  * To invite you to participate in surveys about Shule Direct services or our partner's (participation is always voluntary); and for marketing purposes, where you have agreed to this.

### When we need you for marketing purposes

﻿Shule Direct will only use your information for marketing purposes, or to promote new services, activities or online content where you have expressly agreed to this. This do not include testimonials. When you write in your testimonials about our products or services, please be aware that the information will be used in the testimonials page and not elsewhere.

### Sharing your personal information

﻿We will keep your information confidential except where disclosure is required or permitted by law, to government bodies and law enforcement agencies. Generally, we will only use your information within Shule Direct. However, sometimes Shule Direct engages third parties to process your information on our behalf. We require these third parties to comply strictly with its instructions and not to use your personal information for their own business purposes, unless you have explicitly consented to the use of your personal information in this way.

### Offensive or inappropriate content

﻿If you post or send offensive, inappropriate or objectionable content anywhere on Shule Direct, we may use your personal information to stop such behaviour.

Where Shule Direct reasonably believes that you are or may be in breach of any applicable laws (e.g. because content you have posted may be defamatory), we may use your personal information to inform relevant third parties such as your school about the content and your behaviour.

### Parental Permission

﻿For our student users, please get your parent/guardian's permission before you provide any personal information to Shule Direct. Users without this consent are not allowed to provide us with personal information.

### Holding your personal information

﻿We will hold your personal information on our systems for as long as is necessary for the relevant activity. If you cancel your registration as a Shule Direct member and your account is deleted, your personal information stays on the system for a period of one year for administration purposes before being deleted completed.

Where you contribute material to Shule Direct we will generally only keep your content for as long as is reasonably required for the purpose(s) for which it was submitted.

### Changes to this Privacy Policy

﻿This Privacy Policy may be updated from time to time so you may wish to check it each time you submit personal information to Shule Direct. The date of the most recent revisions will appear on this page. If you do not agree to these changes, please do not continue to use Shule Direct to submit personal information. If material changes are made to the Privacy Policy we will notify you by placing a prominent notice on the website.

**[Contact us](http://www.shuledirect.co.tz/contact) about this Privacy Policy**
